1981 S Wolff St, Denver, 80219 joe@joedalton.io 989.390.4459

# **JOE DALTON**

FRONT-END ENGINEER



## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Hi. I am a passionate front-end engineer with strong problem-solving abilities and attention to detail. I enjoy empathizing with users and building elegant and novel user-friendly interfaces, particularly when highly-interactive and animated. With over 10 years of experience in web app development, I am an expert in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and love building organized and performant applications.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

MAY 2022 - PRESENT

#### Senior Front-end Engineer, CandleScience, Remote (Durham, NC)

- Optimized and further developed the Nuxt/Vue.js website and build pipeline, acting as a JavaScript and general front-end resource for the multi-disciplinary team.
- Designed and implemented user-friendly interfaces, ensuring a seamless user experience and maximizing user engagement and conversion rates.
- Introduced and maintained code quality standards and best practices to ensure high-quality front-end code

APR 2022 - FEB 2023

## Senior Software Engineer, Marketing, Klaviyo, Remote (Boston, MA)

 Worked on and provided technical direction for the marketing-focused properties, including architecting a monorepo and shared component library for the Gatsby/React projects.

AUG 2017 - NOV 2021

## Senior Software Engineer, Spectrum, Denver, CO

- Acting as a shared service, building prototypes and proof-of-concept applications for cross-functional design teams.
- Built shared development tools such as component libraries and platforms, in both React and Vue.js, enabling teams to move faster and with more consistency.

SEP 2016 - AUG 2017

# UX Engineer, Athlinks, Denver, CO

• I was a floating front-end developer, being a reference for front-end best practices across a handful of products, and championing good UX.

JUNE 2015 - MAY 2016

#### Front-end Web Developer, Sequence, San Francisco, CA

- An agency, where I contributed and built small web apps with a team of three.
- Clients included Chipotle, Chevron, Facebook Business, Medtronic, and more.

## **EDUCATION**

AUG 2010 - MAR 2012

M.S. Stem Cell Biology, University of Minnesota

AUG 2007 - JUN 2010

**B.S. Biology, Ferris State University** 

# **SKILLS**

Component-based Architecture (React, Vue.js)



Static Site Generation (Next.js, Gatsby, Nuxt)



State Management (Flux, Redux)



Asynchronous Data Flow (Promises, REST, GraphQL)



Design System Development



Animation (CSS, GSAP, Bodymovin)



Data Visualization



Accessibility



Project Leadership



## LINKS

**Website** 

<u>Github</u>